<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feature
      id="com.zealcore.sd.ose.feature"
      label="Optima Log Analyzer OSE Importer"
      version="2.0.0"
      provider-name="Enea ZealCore AB"
      plugin="com.zealcore.sd.branding"
      os="linux,macosx,solaris,win32">

   <description url="http://www.zealcore.com/prod_systemdebugg.html">
      The Enea Optima Log Analyzer collects and refines information
contained in logs. This is achieved by advanced post processing
of log information, by fusion of different logs, by mapping recorded
information to high level models, and, not the least, by bringing
order to the log exploration and debugging process.
The Enea Optima Log Analyzer can be used during development,
integration, test, deployment, and operation depending on when
the logs have been gathered.
The Enea Optima Log Analyzer lets you create projects and logsets
for tracking down bugs in software. One logset can cover information
from several logs, and a project can manage several logsets,
either from one and the same system collected at different occasions,
from different software versions or e.g., from different nodes
in a distributed system.
The Enea Optima Log Analyzer allows you to make advanced post
processing of data including filtering and advanced searches
that can pinpoint a specific behaviour. The search results are
synchronized with other views and exploring the results is just
a click away. Assertions allow for automatic fault identification,
risks and negative trends. The latter is especially powerful
when the post processing is performed on e.g., logs from different
versions of software for a system – making it possible to detect
subtle behavioural differences between the software versions
which later could lead to system failures or poor performance.
   </description>

   <copyright>
      Copyright (C) 2004-2011 by Enea ZealCore AB. All rights reserved.
   </copyright>

   <license url="license.html">
      Copyright (C) 2004-2011 by Enea ZealCore AB. All rights reserved.

      This Software is furnished under a software license agreement and
      may be used only in accordance with the terms of such agreement.
      Any other use or reproduction is prohibited. No title to and
      ownership of the Software is hereby transferred.

      PROPRIETARY NOTICE
      This Software consists of confidential information.
      Trade secret law and copyright law protect this Software.
      The above notice of copyright on this Software does not indicate
      any actual or intended publication of such Software.
   </license>

   <url>
      <update label="Optima Updates" url="http://iv.enea.se/~integrat/optima-updates"/>
      <discovery label="Optima Updates" url="http://iv.enea.se/~integrat/optima-updates"/>
   </url>

   <requires>
      <import feature="com.zealcore.sd.feature" version="2.0.0" match="greaterOrEqual"/>
   </requires>

   <plugin
         id="com.zealcore.sd.ose.importers"
         download-size="0"
         install-size="0"
         version="2.0.0"
         unpack="false"/>

</feature>
