<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="collection_questions">
        <item>What is Java Collections Framework? List out some benefits of Collections framework?</item>
        <item>What is the benefit of Generics in Collections Framework?</item>
        <item>What are the basic interfaces of Java Collections Framework?</item>
        <item>Why Collection doesn’t extend Cloneable and Serializable interfaces?</item>
        <item>Why Map interface doesn’t extend Collection interface?</item>
        <item>What is an Iterator?</item>
        <item>What is difference between Enumeration and Iterator interface?</item>
        <item>Why there is not method like Iterator.add() to add elements to the collection?</item>
        <item>Why Iterator doesn’t have a method to get next element directly without moving the cursor?</item>
        <item>What is different between Iterator and ListIterator?</item>
        <item>What are different ways to iterate over a list?</item>
        <item>What do you understand by iterator fail-fast property?</item>
        <item>What is difference between fail-fast and failsafe?</item>
        <item>How to avoid ConcurrentModificationException while iterating a collection?</item>
        <item>Why there are no concrete implementations of Iterator interface?</item>
        <item>How HashMap works in Java?</item>
        <item>What is the importance of hashCode() and equals() methods in HashMap?</item>
        <item>Can we use any class as Map key?</item>
        <item>What are different Collection views provided by Map interface?</item>
        <item>What is difference between HashMap and Hashtable?</item>
        <item>How to decide between HashMap and TreeMap?</item>
        <item>What are similarities and difference between ArrayList and Vector?</item>
        <item>What is difference between Array and ArrayList?\n
            When will you use Array over ArrayList?
        </item>
        <item>What is difference between ArrayList and LinkedList?</item>
        <item>Which collection classes provide random access of its elements?</item>
        <item>What is EnumSet?</item>
        <item>Which collection classes are thread-safe?</item>
        <item>What are concurrent Collection Classes?</item>
        <item>What is BlockingQueue?</item>
        <item>What is Queue and Stack, list their differences?</item>
        <item>What is Collections Class?</item>
        <item>What is Comparable and Comparator interface?</item>
        <item>How can we sort a list of Objects?</item>
        <item>While passing a Collection as argument to a function, how can we make sure the function will not be able to modify it?</item>
        <item>How can we create a synchronized collection from given collection?</item>
        <item>What are common algorithms implemented in Collections Framework?</item>
        <item>What is Java Priority Queue?</item>
        
    </string-array>
    
</resources>
