<contexts>
	<context
		id="editors_TimelineBrowser">
		<description>The Time Line browser displays the relative distance between events.</description>
		<topic href="log_analyzer_explore_data.html#log_analyzer_timeline_browser" label="Timeline Browser"/>
	</context>
	<context
		id="editors_GanttChart">
		<description>The Gantt Chart displays task executions in a Gantt like diagram.</description>
		<topic href="log_analyzer_explore_data.html#log_analyzer_gantt_chart" label="Gantt Chart"/>
	</context>
	<context
		id="editors_TextBrowser">
		<description>The Text browser displays the events and their properties as rows of text.</description>
		<topic href="log_analyzer_explore_data.html#log_analyzer_text_browser" label="Text Browser"/>
	</context>
	<context
		id="editors_SequenceDiagramBrowser">
		<description>The sequence diagram shows, as parallel vertical lines, processes, objects or actors (here called actors) that live simultaneously, and, as horizontal arrows, the messages exchanged between them, in the order in which they occur.</description>
		<topic href="log_analyzer_explore_data.html#log_analyzer_sequence_diagram" label="Sequence Diagram"/>
	</context>
	<context
		id="views_ResourceNavigator">
		<description>The Resource Navigator display a tree of resources/artifacts found in a Logset.</description>
		<topic href="log_analyzer_explore_data.html#log_analyzer_resource_navigator" label="Resource Navigator"/>
	</context>
	<context
		id="wizard_ImportWizard">
		<description>When using the Import Wizard, all events in the log file must be formed on the same pattern of fields. There can be any number of fields in an event as long as they appear in the same order. When running the Import Wizard, the user specifies how many fields there are per event and each field is defined by the properties name, data type and delimiter. When fields are defined, the preview is updated to make it easier to verify that the import will be correct. For more information, see Enea Optima Log Analyzer reference under Importing data</description>
		<topic href="log_analyzer_import_data.html#log_analyzer_import_wizard" label="Import Wizard"/>
	</context>
	<context
		id="dialog_BasicSearch">
		<description>Use this dialog to perform basic searches over log events and artifacts in the current logset</description>
		<topic href="log_analyzer_search.html" label="Basic search"/>
	</context>
	<context
		id="wizard_NewAssertion">
		<description>Use this wizard to create and maintain assertions</description>
		<topic href="log_analyzer_assertions.html" label="Assertions"/>
	</context>
	<context
		id="dialog_NewAssertionSet">
		<description>Use this dialog to create a new assertion set</description>
		<topic href="log_analyzer_assertions.html" label="Assertions"/>
	</context>
	<context
		id="dialog_NewAssertion">
		<description>Use this dialog to create a new Assertion</description>
		<topic href="log_analyzer_assertions.html" label="Assertions"/>
	</context>
	<context
		id="dialog_NewAdvancedAssertion">
		<description>Use this dialog to create a new Script Assertion</description>
		<topic href="log_analyzer_assertions.html" label="Assertions"/>
	</context>
</contexts>
